<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.1.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:8081/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:8081/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2021-01-16T22:53:49-06:00</updated><id>http://localhost:8081/feed.xml</id><title type="html">TreborTech</title><subtitle>Nobody should ever have to solve a problem twice.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Mobile WIFI</title><link href="http://localhost:8081/technology/2021/01/13/mobile-wifi.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Mobile WIFI" /><published>2021-01-13T09:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2021-01-13T09:00:00-06:00</updated><id>http://localhost:8081/technology/2021/01/13/mobile-wifi</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:8081/technology/2021/01/13/mobile-wifi.html">&lt;p&gt;In an effort to stay on the road longer and possibly work from the road I needed an internet option. Instead of tethering my phone or having another phone dedicated to provide network connectivity, I decided to build a portable network football.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Below I outline how I built this network football.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/mobile-wifi-1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Mobile WIFI&quot; height=&quot;300&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/mobile-wifi-2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Mobile WIFI&quot; height=&quot;300&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Requirements&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Dedicated internet system&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Works with 12v DC system&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ruggedized&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Mobile (at campsite)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hardware list&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;$20 - Waterproof container - Bass Pro Shops Watertight Equipment Case&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;$330 - &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B07Z5LNWY6/ref=ppx_yo_dt_b_search_asin_title?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;psc=1&quot;&gt;COMBO 4G/LTE Router&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;$7 - &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B07MT3VZXZ/ref=ppx_yo_dt_b_search_asin_title?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;psc=1&quot;&gt;SRP-SMA Male to RP-SMA Female Bulkhead Mount RG316&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;$7 - &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B07MJQWH8S/ref=ppx_yo_dt_b_search_asin_title?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;psc=1&quot;&gt;SMA Female Bulkhead Mount to SMA Male&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;$99 - &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B01801BJ7I/ref=ppx_yo_dt_b_search_asin_title?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;psc=1&quot;&gt;External Wide Band Log Periodic Yagi Antenna&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;$13 - &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B07W8MVNSJ/ref=ppx_yo_dt_b_search_asin_title?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;psc=1&quot;&gt;6 Way Blade Fuse Box&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;$10 - &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B072BXB2Y8/ref=ppx_yo_dt_b_search_asin_title?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;psc=1&quot;&gt; 10 Pairs DC Power Pigtail Cable Wire&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;$13 - &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B07V6NJ37P/ref=ppx_yo_dt_b_search_asin_title?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;psc=1&quot;&gt;SAE Power Socket Sidewall Port&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition to the list above you will need to get data plan sim from a phone provider. I use T-Mobile so it was simple to add to my plan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;fw-bold&quot;&gt;Container:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Any water proof container will work but I found this one worked great for what I needed. The bright orange color is great so I don’t forget it when I leave the campsite. If you build a network football I highly suggest going with the brightest color possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;fw-bold&quot;&gt;WIFI Router Choice:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is an expensive option but I don’t regret it. I spent months watching reviews of 4G routers to finally decide to pull the trigger on this one. Nobody seemed to regret purchasing it and neither do I. Easy to set up and the performance is great.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;fw-bold&quot;&gt;Antenna options:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To keep the container watertight I had to move the antennas outside the box. This was easier than I thought it would be. Two types of extension cables are required. 1 set is for the 4G blade antennas and 1 set is for the WIFI antennas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I did purchase the Yagi antenna just in case I’m on the edge of a cell-tower range. It will simply connect to the same connector the blade antennas connect to.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;fw-bold&quot;&gt;Power option:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I’m boondocking it’s best to have everything run off 12v DC. It’s much more efficient to run products directly with 12v versus using the inverter or the generator.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nice thing with electronics, most are 12v with power adapter converting AC to DC. All I had to do what remove the power adapter with a 12v DC connection. To ensure I don’t overload the router (a very expensive router) I put a small fuse panel between the power coming into the box and the router.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The fuse panel receives power directly from the SAE connector on the side. To get power to this box I converted a normal extension cord, using only the white/black wires, and added an SAE connectors on both ends. My camper has an SAE connector on the battery box and just like that, we have the internet.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;fw-bold&quot;&gt;Additional items in picture:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The keen eye will notice a few other items I haven’t listed above under hardware. They are items outside of the wifi connection. I added two LED lights to the side and a switch on top to turn them on and off.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;fw-bold&quot;&gt;Building it:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just connect it all together&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="technology" /><summary type="html">In an effort to stay on the road longer and possibly work from the road I needed an internet option. Instead of tethering my phone or having another phone dedicated to provide network connectivity, I decided to build a portable network football. Below I outline how I built this network football.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">FIDO Introduction</title><link href="http://localhost:8081/technology/2021/01/11/fido-intro.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="FIDO Introduction" /><published>2021-01-11T09:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2021-01-11T09:00:00-06:00</updated><id>http://localhost:8081/technology/2021/01/11/fido-intro</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:8081/technology/2021/01/11/fido-intro.html">&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;blockquote class=&quot;blockquote&quot;&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Never has the world been more dependent on the internet, and never has it been more attacked than in 2020. In fact, it proved to be a year where trust in many of our systems was challenged. Yet I remain an eternal optimist and believe that we can transform the hard lessons learned in 2020&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/blockquote&gt;
  &lt;figcaption class=&quot;blockquote-footer&quot;&gt;
    &lt;cite title=&quot;Source Title&quot;&gt;Stina Ehrensvard&lt;/cite&gt;
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="technology" /><summary type="html">Never has the world been more dependent on the internet, and never has it been more attacked than in 2020. In fact, it proved to be a year where trust in many of our systems was challenged. Yet I remain an eternal optimist and believe that we can transform the hard lessons learned in 2020 Stina Ehrensvard</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Why Bitcoin</title><link href="http://localhost:8081/technology/blockchain/2021/01/05/your-first-bitcoin.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Why Bitcoin" /><published>2021-01-05T09:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2021-01-05T09:00:00-06:00</updated><id>http://localhost:8081/technology/blockchain/2021/01/05/your-first-bitcoin</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:8081/technology/blockchain/2021/01/05/your-first-bitcoin.html">&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;blockquote class=&quot;blockquote&quot;&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Code talks, Talk walks.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/blockquote&gt;
  &lt;figcaption class=&quot;blockquote-footer&quot;&gt;
    &lt;cite title=&quot;Source Title&quot;&gt;Andreas Antonopoulos&lt;/cite&gt;
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;h5 main-page-text lh-lg fw-lighter&quot;&gt;
You hear them talking about it on the news. You see tweets in your feed talking about. YouTube knows you're thinking about it and suggests CryptoDaily.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!--more--&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;h6 main-page-text lh-lg fw-bold&quot;&gt;
What is it?
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;h6 main-page-text lh-lg fw-bold&quot;&gt;
Why does it matter?
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;h6 main-page-text lh-lg fw-bold&quot;&gt;
And how do I get in on the action?
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;post-body-outline&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;h4 main-page-text fw-bold&quot;&gt;
What is it?
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;h6 main-page-text fw-lighter&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;lh-base&quot;&gt;
Bitcoin, blockchain, digital gold, crypto-currency. You will hear many names for it and you might not care to pay attention to it, but make no mistake these terms will soon be in your vocablary regardless of who you are. For those of us who remember being introduced to the internet and how the world we live in today was unimaginable, this is bigger than that.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;lh-base&quot;&gt;
Back in the early 90's e-mail, smartphone, webpage, url where strange words that confused us when used. Today they are normalized and used without second thought. Remember when you first heard Google it?
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;lh-base&quot;&gt;
These are just a few examples of how technology and it's terminology integrates so seemlessly into our lives. Bitcoin and cryptocurrency are two terms that are well on there way to becomming the next normalized technology terms and technology.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;lh-base&quot;&gt;
The technology behind cryptocurrency hits at the core of our everyday lives. Currency.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;iframe class=&quot;rounded float-start&quot; width=&quot;420&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/vUOpKfCuV_E&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="technology" /><category term="blockchain" /><summary type="html">Code talks, Talk walks. Andreas Antonopoulos You hear them talking about it on the news. You see tweets in your feed talking about. YouTube knows you're thinking about it and suggests CryptoDaily.</summary></entry></feed>